

matteo@rizzi.xyz @matteounitn:matrix.org



Bachelor in Computer Science, Junior Research Scientist

Born in 1998, 30 September, I work as a Junior Research Scientist in the <u>Security</u> and <u>Trust</u> unit at <u>Fondazione Bruno Kessler</u>. I joined the S&T unit to explore and improve TLS analysis and delve into identity management. I am working concurrently between FBK and the Istituto Poligrafico e Zecca dello Stato.

Experiences

Fondazione Bruno Kessler (Trento, Italy)

Junior Research Scientist • Feb, 2021 - Present

Security analysis of the TLS deployments of <u>IPZS</u> projects, TLS Analysis in Android Apps and TLS tool enhancement within the Security & Trust research unit.

Internship ● *Feb, 2020 - May, 2020*

Study and improvement of TLS analysis tools within the Security & Trust research unit.

Futuro & Conoscenza S.r.l. (Trento & Rome, Italy)

Junior Research Scientist • Jul, 2021 - Present

Collaboration between <u>Fondazione Bruno Kessler</u> and <u>IPZS</u> to promote the exchange of know-how and competences in the field of security technologies (material and digital) such as identification and anti-counterfeiting, as well as the creation of a center for the coordination and exploitation of research.

Papers

A Modular and Extensible Framework for Securing TLS

in 12th ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy, CODASPY ● Apr, 2022

Matteo Rizzi, Salvatore Manfredi, Giada Sciarretta, Silvio Ranise.

Projects

Multi-CIE System

Ideation and creation of the CieID App Multi-CIE ● Jan, 2022 - March, 2022

The CieID App allows users to verify themselves for public services in Italy by using the CIE Card, commonly known as Carta di Identità Elettronica (eID card). Worked as part of a team to develop the best method for storing multiple eID cards in the APP while keeping the highest level of security and determining the optimum balance of security and usability.

<u>breaking-telegram</u>

PoC script to break Telegram ● 2021

Simple PoC script that allows you to exploit telegram's "send with timer" feature by saving any media received with this functionality, automatically.

TLSAssistant

Version 1.3 and 2.0 to 2.3 • 2020 - Present

Fully-featured tool that combines state-of-the-art TLS analyzers with a report system that suggests appropriate mitigations and shows the full set of viable attacks.

iHashDNA

Perceptual hashing library in python ● 2020 - 2022 (Suspended)

Python library to easily check if two images are similar without machine learning by using Perceptual Hashing (phash and whash combined), with ban and unban image system.

Minor Works

Mallodroid

Conversion in Python 3 and enhancements ● 2020 - 2021

telegram-deep-fakes-bot

Easy implementation and use of the first order model ● 2020

Rappresentanti Bot

HelpDesk Telegram bot to support DISI Students in University of Trento ● 2019

Education

University of Trento (Trento, Italy)

Bachelor of Computer Science • Sept, 2017 - Mar, 2021

Thesis in TLS Analyzers for Android Apps - State-of-the-art Analysis and Integration in TLSAssistant.

I.I.S. Primo Levi (Badia Polesine, Italy)

High School Diploma ● Sept, 2012 - Sept, 2017

Final elaborate in *psychoanalysis of James Joyce and the artificial intelligences*.

Certifications

CyberWiser - CyberRange And Capacity Building in CyberSecurity

Module	Date	Certificate
P-01-M-01	May 19, 2021	<u>Download</u>
P-01-M-02	May 20, 2021	<u>Download</u>
P-02	May 20, 2021	<u>Download</u>
P-03	May 20, 2021	<u>Download</u>
P-04	May 25, 2021	<u>Download</u>
P-05	June 4, 2021	<u>Download</u>
P-06	June 4, 2021	Download

First Certificate

Cambridge Assessment English - B2 ● Apr, 2017

ECDL Base

ECDL / ICDL Certification ● May, 2016

Programming Skills

Python, Java, C (and C++), SQL	Advanced	
Kotlin, PHP	Intermediate	
RUST	Basic (willing to improve)	
JS, PolyML, R, ASM	Basic	

Knowledge Level

Interests and Soft Skills

Work Interests

Language

What i really want to do in my future ● 2022

I am passionate about *CyberSecurity, Privacy, Forensics and Digital Identity*, as well as the solutions that embrace these areas, which include (but are *not limited to*) *Security Protocol Analysis, Access Control, Zero-Trust and Zero-Knowledge methods, Malware Analysis and Al-Powered CyberSecurity*. I am particularly intrigued by the idea of developing novel solutions and conducting scientific research in these fields.

University of Trento (Trento, Italy)

Student Representative for DISI • Nov, 2018 - Nov, 2022

Department Of Information Engineering And Computer Science



